<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Hello, World</title>
    <subtitle>My expositions against the world!!</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://ohjunseung.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ohjunseung.github.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-04-30T13:25:15+07:00</updated>
    <id>https://ohjunseung.github.io/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Correlation of Minimum Wage and Food Price</title>
        <published>2025-04-30T13:25:15+07:00</published>
        <updated>2025-04-30T13:25:15+07:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alexander Matthew
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ohjunseung.github.io/min-wage/"/>
        <id>https://ohjunseung.github.io/min-wage/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://ohjunseung.github.io/min-wage/">&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I proposed a little thesis inside my head: what if the minimum wage of a country is calibrated against their food prices?
Let&#x27;s say an hourly rate for human work is equal to a plate of lunch. We may constrain that a little more, a plate of dish
in a shopping center, hawker center, or something along these lines.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in Indonesia, we might say the food price range would be around 30k to 60k Rupiah. Take the average from that number,
and to make it simpler, the proposed rate would be 50,000.00 Rupiah. That means 50k would buy your time for an hour.
For Indonesians out there, the calculation would be 40 hours a week (normal work time) times 50k Rupiah.
2 million times 4 weeks, 8 million Rupiah a month, should be the minimum wage (UMR). Of course you can adjust according to your region.
You&#x27;re welcome to test this thesis against your own country. Is it above or below the proposed rate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that example above, we know that the Indonesian minimum wage is less than our proposed value. This might also mean that
most Indonesian are underpaid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;applying-to-economics&quot;&gt;Applying to Economics&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reach this ideal, proposed value, there are two options we can take.
First, just make the pay higher, like most capitalist countries. Higher goods prices are equal to higher pay.
Second, make the goods cheaper so the buying power increases without any wage increase. This sounds more like socialist play.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most ideal would be increasing wages and reducing food prices. That might be one of the most impossible things to do.
The other extreme would be reducing labor pay and increasing food prices. What country would that be?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Should password be constrained?</title>
        <published>2022-12-06T12:12:05+07:00</published>
        <updated>2022-12-06T12:12:05+07:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alexander Matthew
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ohjunseung.github.io/password/"/>
        <id>https://ohjunseung.github.io/password/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://ohjunseung.github.io/password/">&lt;p&gt;Password is one of the most common ways to authenticate ourselves online. Different applications, either web or mobile,
all have various constraints for their password input. Most of them need only the alphabet (hence the word in &quot;password&quot;).
Some require different casing, numbers, and symbols. Length is also one of their criteria, a minimum of six characters
and a maximum of 32 characters. Is this really necessary? What&#x27;s the benefit?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, a longer password means harder for attackers to brute-force. But a maximum of 32 characters? Does it really make any
difference? Is it smaller to store in the database, hence doing it this way?
I even found an app that only allows a maximum eight-character password (or maybe exactly 8, idk).
Let&#x27;s see how we store passwords nowadays to prove (or disprove) the idea.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;password-storing&quot;&gt;Password Storing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one in their right mind will store any password verbatim. &quot;yourPassword&quot; would never be stored as &quot;yourPassword&quot;.
We usually use a hashing algorithm to convert plaintext (password) into ciphertext (random text). Most common ones are,
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Argon2&quot;&gt;Argon2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Bcrypt&quot;&gt;bcrypt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Scrypt&quot;&gt;scrypt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
I won&#x27;t talk about how password hashing works; you can read more &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Cryptographic_hash_function#Password_verification&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, the constraint might be derived from the limitation of the password hashing algorithm. Like bcrypt for example,
have a maximum of 72 bytes input, practically 50 characters which are more than the &quot;typical&quot; maximum online.
Something like Argon2 can handle a huge input size. Google limits its password input
between 8 to 100 characters. Very logical; thinking something like argon2 can handle this input.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, hashing algorithm will produce the same size output. So, the argument for saving storage by limiting password
input is pretty much invalid.
Hashing algorithm also takes raw bytes as input, so including symbols and changing letter casing doesn&#x27;t really matter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s try Argon2 in Argon2id mode with some input examples. Here I specify the output length to be 16 bytes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#fcf0ca;color:#282828aa;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;parameters: $argon2id$v=19$m=16,t=2,p=1$
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;salt: kpYc2O20J0rLlpNZ
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;input                           -&amp;gt; output in hex
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;---
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;exactly8                        -&amp;gt; 9e7ccabb91d20a45c875d1f7cd974437
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;atozonly                        -&amp;gt; 67094c5c3a96cb205621d62a545666ae
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;AtozOnly                        -&amp;gt; 020f12120beec77286da2b96b67d6b4d
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;atoZwith+symbols=?              -&amp;gt; 69d9692f93a2e05ffb0ce512079ee632
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;atoZwith+symbols=?and123        -&amp;gt; 63d7094636891d4ca1e4a72e4e518b34
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;completelyrandomtextbutverylong -&amp;gt; fbabc6b60e7cce389724d537d3fc2772
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;---
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see, password input doesn&#x27;t have any effect on the hasher output. This means that storage size doesn&#x27;t change
between inputs. All of the examples would produce precisely 16 bytes. We can safely say password doesn&#x27;t need to be constrained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The security of passwords depends on which algorithm is used and how you implement the algorithm. Any flaw in the algorithm
would compromise security. Improper use of the technology would also create flaws.
So this matter more than how complex your password input is. I&#x27;m not a security expert, and my advice might not be valid,
but usually, something long is enough to slow down brute-force attacks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;read-more&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I could use any random word or phrase for my password, then?&quot;. Yes, you could, but you shouldn&#x27;t.
&quot;Should I remove every constraint for usability? How about security?&quot;. If you have these kinds of questions in mind, checkout
this talk on USENIX Security &#x27;16 about &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;vf37jh3dV2I&quot;&gt;zxcvbn: Low-Budget Password Strength Estimation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Daniel Lowe Wheeler.
Or read &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;dropbox&#x2F;zxcvbn&quot;&gt;zxcvbn repository&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Goodbye 3G, long live 2G networks.</title>
        <published>2022-10-22T12:10:00+07:00</published>
        <updated>2022-10-22T12:10:00+07:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alexander Matthew
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ohjunseung.github.io/3g-2g/"/>
        <id>https://ohjunseung.github.io/3g-2g/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://ohjunseung.github.io/3g-2g/">&lt;p&gt;Indonesia decided to kill 3G networks, but keep older 2G standards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-why-why&quot;&gt;Why. Why. Why???&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I don&#x27;t f*ing know.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime ago &quot;they&quot; decided to stop supporting 3G devices, while the coverage of LTE networks still isn&#x27;t stable
enough (subject to bias). Major telecom companies are doing this willingly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe we can speculate on the reasoning behind this. Your allocated radio frequencies are not enough to accommodate
the 5G radio, so kill 3G instead and use their spectrum. Why don&#x27;t we ban 2G band first? Ah, distribution of
client devices might be the case. A lot people in rural area still uses 2G, so kill 3G instead. According to &quot;something&quot;
or &quot;someone&quot;, a lot (read: most) people uses of VoIP to make calls, so kill 3G instead (definitely not me, I use both equally).
Why the hell we need to care about people, so kill 3G instead.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
This is definitely just a political decision to manage radio spectrum and support of the New Radio, they said.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;voice-calls&quot;&gt;Voice calls.&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you can connect to the Internet you can call almost anyone (also read: almost no one) with VoIP.
Don&#x27;t get me started on this, as this is pretty much straightforward *wink.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GSM&#x2F;2G has been the standard for communication since &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;w&#x2F;index.php?title=2G&amp;amp;oldid=1114491643#cite_note-Radiolinja&amp;#x27;s_History-1&quot;&gt;1991&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
They even have evolved into EDGE to support higher data rates. Now, 3G upgraded that in voice and also in mobile data.
So much sense that we should kill the older stuff, no? Or maybe I&#x27;m the one that doesn&#x27;t have much sense, you decide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Voice_over_LTE&quot;&gt;VoLTE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the best thing to do these days. Practically though, ...&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
In my case, having a VoLTE capable phone and provider should be good right? Wrong! Definitely wrong. The network support sucks.
All of my calls (as the time of writing) never get through via VoLTE. So, for me at least, it just doesn&#x27;t work.
If VoLTE is not the solution, VoNR (Voice over 5G) must not be either *wink.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-affects-users-me&quot;&gt;How it affects users (me).&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of voice calls here are still using 2G networks. This means that our cellphone needs to move from whatever network
it currently in to 2G networks. For example, we are using the Internet over LTE to play
time sensitive game (read: chess), suddenly someone tries to call you via cellphone number, before the ringing signal
can even get through, your phone will switch to 2G meaning that you lost the connection (read: lose the game). Even after
the call ends, it takes time to switch back to LTE and get any Internet connection. This also means when we are on a call
with someone, there is no way to use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.google.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Google&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to search how&#x27;s the weather today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least for today, I don&#x27;t f*ing know why this must be a thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
